apsjobs.gov.au 2012-05-25

# APSjobs - Privacy Statement

##  General Privacy Statement

**APS jobs** is owned, managed and maintained by the Australian Public Service Commission (the Administrator) on behalf of the Commonwealth of Australia (the Commonwealth). 

**APS jobs** is a website designed to assist the recruitment of Australian Government employees and incorporates the Public Service Gazette. 

This privacy policy applies to all the publicly accessible pages on the website. Responsibility for the privacy policies or practices of third party sites, linked to **APS jobs** is beyond the control of the Commonwealth. 

Any information provided by users of **APS jobs** will be treated in accordance with the Guidelines for Federal and ACT Government Websites (Guidelines) used by the Federal Privacy Commissioner. 

##  What information is recorded about my visiting this site?

When you look at this website ([www.APSjobs.gov.au](http://www.apsjobs.gov.au/)), our service provider makes a record of your visit. 

The following system information may be collected: 

  * IP (Internet Protocol) address of the machine which has accessed it.
  * Top-level domain name (eg. .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc)
  * IP Address of your server
  * Date and time of your visit to the site
  * Pages accessed
  * Previous website visited
  * Type of browser and operating system you have.

The information collected during each visit may be used for statistical purposes only, mainly for the purpose of producing reports in order to identify patterns of usage of **APS jobs**. This will assist us in improving the website. 

##  Cookies

**APS jobs** uses a cookie to maintain contact through a session. The cookie allows **APS jobs** to recognise you as an individual as you move from one page of the website to another. The cookie will expire when the browser session is closed or the computer is shut down. No attempt will be made to identify anonymous users or their browsing activities unless legally compelled to do so, such as in the event of an investigation. 

More detailed information about cookies can be found at the site of the Federal Privacy Commissioner at [ www.privacy.gov.au/internet/internet_privacy/index.html](http://www.privacy.gov.au/internet/internet_privacy/index.html)

##  Communicating with the APSjobs Helpdesk by email

If you email the **APS jobs** Helpdesk your email address will only be used for the purpose for which you provided it. If your query draws attention to problems with **APS jobs**, we may choose to draw this issue to wider attention, but will do this in a way that does not identify you.

Email is not a secure way to communicate. You should be aware of this when sending personal information to us via email. Also, emails are official records and may be monitored by the Administrators. If this is of concern to you then you should use other methods of communication with the Administrators.

## APSjobs Privacy statement

##  Scope of this Privacy statement

This statement applies to personal information held by **APS jobs**.

##  Our commitment to protecting privacy and confidential information

**APS jobs** is committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information it holds. The Administrators of the site (the Australian Public Service Commission) are bound by the Information Privacy Principles set out in the _Privacy Act 1988_. 

Commission employees are subject to the APS Values and Code of Conduct and if they disclose official information without authority in breach of Public Service Regulation 2.1 they may face disciplinary sanctions including, in the most serious cases, termination of employment. 

Commission service providers are bound contractually to observe the Information Privacy Principles. 

Current and former employees of the Commission and service providers to the Commission are covered by section 70 of the _Crimes Act 1914_ , which provides for criminal penalties for unauthorised disclosure of official information.

We have internal policies on privacy, security, email and internet usage, and fraud control. We draw these to the attention of new staff and regularly remind all staff.

##  What kinds of personal information do we hold?

The main kind of personal information that we may hold is information provided directly by individuals.

Information provided directly to us on a voluntary basis includes registration details, work history details, employment preference details and inquiries by individuals to **APS jobs**.

##  How do we use personal information?

Where we solicit information, the purpose for which it is collected will be stated on any form or request by us. If you volunteer information, the purpose will be obvious from the context. 

Personal information that we hold may be shared for the purpose for which it was obtained, or for related purposes such as statistical analysis, reporting and evaluation.

##  To whom may we disclose your personal information?

Information collected at this website is for the purposes of recruitment and employment activities with respect to APS vacancies and potential vacancies. Information may be disclosed to persons involved with carrying out those activities.

This may include but not be limited to an APS employee’s current employer or Agency, or another APS Agency, or a person or body authorised by an APS Agency to assist with or provide recruitment services.

##  Access to and correction of your records

The _Freedom of Information Act 1982_ gives you the right to see the personal information we hold about you, with some exceptions. Under the Information Privacy Principles you can contact us at any time and ask us to amend your information if you consider it is inaccurate or incomplete. 

For more information, contact the Privacy Contact Officer on 02 6202 3570.

##  Management and security of personal information

The Administrator of **APS jobs** takes reasonable steps to ensure the security of the personal information held. Hard copy records are stored in a secure environment. Access to the Commission’s premises is controlled. Access privileges to the **APS jobs** website electronic records is limited to authorised persons by password controls and personal identifiers. The Commission’s IT security is regularly tested.

Information provided is transmitted via a secure electronic interface and registrations for the **APS jobs** website is lodged through secure websites. The apsjobs website warns visitors that e-mail is not a secure way to communicate and to be aware of this when sending personal information to the **APS jobs** website via e-mail.

All **APS jobs** records are kept in accordance with the _Archives Act 1983_.

## Queries and complaints

For more information about privacy in general, you can visit the Federal Privacy Commissioner's website [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/). To clarify any privacy issues or make a complaint if you think we have breached your privacy rights, please contact our Privacy Contact Officer in writing 16 Furzer St, Phillip, ACT 2606 or by phoning 02 6202 3570.

If you are not satisfied, you can contact the Federal Privacy Commissioner by:

  * phoning 1300 363 992 for the cost of a local call
  * emailing [privacy@privacy.gov.au](mailto:privacy@privacy.gov.au)
  * writing to the Federal Privacy Commissioner, GPO Box 5218 Sydney NSW 1042

Our Privacy policy may change from time to time

The Commission regularly reviews all its policies and procedures. As a result we may change this Privacy Statement and any more detailed statements applying to particular classes of records from time to time.

Back
